Excessive rhytides in this area may indicate,
しわのレベルでは、ここにあまりにも多くのしわがあると、それは
issues of dehydration or anxiety.
脱水症状や不安の問題を意味します。
Transverse worry lines are also, importantly, associated with issues
心配の線は、胃の問題とも関連しています。
of gastric origin.
胃の問題。
A deeply etched line on the right side may
非常に目立つ直線は、
manifest as a hepatic issue related to repressed anger.
肝臓レベルでの抑圧された怒りの問題として現れることがあります。
On the left, this corresponds to the splenic region.
左側は脾臓のレベルです。
Excessive horizontal rhytides, such as these,
このように、またはこのように、あまりにも多くの水平方向の心配は、
may indicate an allergic predisposition.
アレルギーの問題を表すことがあります。
Allergic manifestations in the periorbital area, or specifically here.
この周り、アレルギー、ここにアレルギー。
If the nasal tip presents with a bluish hue, this may be associated with libido.
鼻が性欲に関連して青みがかった場合。
Periorbital hyperpigmentation or edema, if presenting as bluish, brown, or swollen,
目の下のクマ、つまり色、青みがかったり、茶色かったり、腫れていたりする場合、
may indicate either a renal deficiency,
それは腎臓の機能不全であるか、
or an issue with elimination.
それは排泄の問題です。
of urea, or a purely eliminatory dysfunction
尿素の、またはそれは純粋に
of the kidney. If the hue is dark blue, it may
腎臓の排泄の問題です。もしそれが濃い青色であれば、それは
be indicative of a depressive state. A yellowish discoloration may suggest a hepatobiliary issue.
うつ病の問題の兆候である可能性があります。黄色は、肝胆道の問題である可能性があります。
If they
もしそれらが
are brown or black, consider a pancreatic involvement. What are referred to as the lines of
茶色、黒色であれば、膵臓との関連に注意してください。ここに「カラスの足跡」と呼ばれる線は、
the
腎臓、肝臓などの臓器の
crow's feet here, may indicate a deeper visceral imbalance
より深い不均衡を
involving organs such as the kidney or the liver.
示しています。
or the stomach. These appearing lines here may
または胃のレベルがこのように現れる場合、それは
manifest
毒性のある消化器系の状態、または肺の状態を表すことがあります。
as either a toxic digestive state or a pulmonary condition. Consider
ここに小さな静脈が破裂している人がいる場合、彼らはより良く
individuals who
酸素を取り込もうとしているので、肝臓と腸のレベルで確認してください。
present with telangiectasias or ruptured venules in this area; they are, in essence, attempting to improve
鼻の先端が真っ赤な場合、それは心臓です。もしここに非常に強い線が
their oxygenation. Investigate the liver and the intestine, specifically at the level
非常に目立つようにある場合、それは腎臓または膵臓に関連しています。
of the
女性の場合、顎が滑らかでないように見えることがありますが、
nasal tip. If it is intensely red, consider cardiac involvement, especially if you observe very pronounced
それはホルモンの不均衡を表しています。唇のレベルでは、時には
here, very marked like this, it is related to the spleen or related to the pancreas.
すぼめた唇が見られることがあり、それは胃の兆候です。
In
ここが厚くなっている場合も、胃の兆候です。
women, sometimes we see here as if the chin were not smooth and
ここに口角炎がある場合、それはカンジダ症の可能性の兆候です。
this represents
知っているでしょう、このようにひび割れていて、少し白っぽい場合、それは電気的です。
hormonal imbalances. At the level of the lips, you can sometimes have
唇のレベルでは、時には
pursed lips, a gastric sign. We
すぼめた唇が見られることがあり、それは胃の兆候です。
can also have a thickening here, also a sign of gastric issues.
ここが厚くなっている場合も、胃の兆候です。
You can have angular cheilitis here, which is a sign of possible
ここに口角炎がある場合、それはカンジダ症の可能性の兆候です。
candidiasis.
知っているでしょう、このようにひび割れていて、少し白っぽい場合、それは電気的です。
here.
ここに。
A kind of discoloration here with a red border,
ここに赤色の縁取りを伴う一種の変色があり、
pancreas or hyperglycemia, the lips
膵臓または糖分の過剰、唇が
very, very red, a vitamin B depletion, a dryness around
非常に赤く、ビタミンBの枯渇、鼻の周りの皮膚の乾燥。
the skin around
鼻の周りの
the nose.
皮膚。
straw-colored skin, possibly precancerous signs. The lips themselves represent
藁色の肌は、前癌状態の兆候かもしれません。唇自体は
an
腸の
intestinal state. You can sometimes have spots like that, it can be
状態を表しています。時々、このような斑点が見られることがありますが、それは
intestinal problems
腸の問題、
or cardiac issues. People who have this here, it can be an excess
または心臓の問題である可能性があります。ここにこのようなものがある人は、喫煙のしすぎである可能性があります。
due to tobacco use.
喫煙のしすぎ。
Bluish lip color, a pulmonary issue,
唇が青みがかった色をしている場合、肺に問題があり、
insufficient oxygen absorption.
酸素の吸収が不十分です。
A very red color, as we said, vitamin B depletion in children.
非常に赤い色は、先ほど言ったように、子供のビタミンBの枯渇です。
You see here, a poorly defined pink area.
ここを見てください、境界が不明瞭なピンク色です。
When there is too much sugar, we often observe this pattern.
糖分が多すぎると、このようにたくさんなります。
And in fact, it creates a kind of small, poorly defined border, like that.
そして実際、このように境界が不明瞭な小さな縁取りができます。
This indicates a possible pancreatic problem due to hyperglycemia.
それは、おそらく膵臓の糖分過剰の問題を示しています。
Oral thrush, or candidiasis, at the corners of the lips.
口角の鵞口瘡、またはカンジダ症。
And you still have aphthae that can occur internally,
そして、口の中にできる口内炎もありますが、
which are a disturbance associated with...
それは、
a mineral deficiency, manganese,
ミネラルの低下、マンガン、
B vitamin
ビタミンB、
and calcium. Here, we can clearly see
そしてカルシウムに関連する障害です。ここでは、
this entire fascial relationship with the eye,
目との顔面全体の関係がよくわかります。
Tenon's capsule.
テノン嚢。
The eye is
目は、
an exteriorized brain.
外在化した脳です。
It comes directly from your third
それはあなたの第三脳室から直接来ています。
ventricle. It's a dural fascial
脳室。それは、体のさまざまな筋膜との
relationship with the different
硬膜の顔面関係です。なぜなら、
fascia of the body. Because there is a part
テノン嚢と呼ばれるものを含む部分があるからです。
with, among others, what is called Tenon's
テノン嚢。顔面全体の関係。
capsule. An entire fascial relationship.
顔面全体の関係。それは、目の不均衡が
This means that an imbalance of the eye
姿勢に現れることを意味します。
manifests in posture. You have a postural eye and you have a dominant eye
姿勢に現れます。姿勢の目と、
which is not necessarily your postural eye. You have an arterial eye and a venous eye. But
必ずしも姿勢の目ではない優位な目があります。
in the eye, you also have different colors. There is a sympathetic-parasympathetic relationship
動脈の目と静脈の目があります。しかし、
which expresses vitality, it can express toxemia, it can express metabolic balance.
レベルでは
If the sclera is yellow, it can express
目には、さまざまな色があります。交感神経と副交感神経の関係があり、
a pre-phase...
それは生命力、毒血症、代謝のバランスを表すことがあります。
In women, sometimes, at a given moment, a little before the ovulation phase,
もし強膜が黄色い場合、それは
we can see something changing in the eye, slightly yellow.
ある段階を...
Well, that can express the pre-ovulatory phase, thus the phase before ovulation.
女性の場合、排卵期の少し前のある時期に、
Something is being prepared in relation to the liver, estrogens, and the entire system.
目にわずかに黄色く変化するものが見られることがあります。
We can also see if the yellowing can express Gilbert's syndrome.
これは、排卵前の黄体形成期を表すことがあります。
It's a problem with the transit of biliary stools in the space of 10.
肝臓、エストロゲン、そして全身のシステムに関連して、何かが準備されています。
On peut voir aussi si les jaunes, ça peut exprimer le syndrome de Gilbert.
また、黄色い場合、それはジルベール症候群を表すこともあります。
C'est un problème de transit des selles biliaires dans l'espace de 10.
これは、胆汁の排泄が10の空間で滞る問題です。
So, it's in the quality of the bilirubin transformation phase.
つまり、ビリルビンの変換段階の質の問題です。
If the sclera has a bluish-white color, it
もし強膜が白青色の場合、それは
is a pulmonary issue.
肺の問題です。
If it's slightly brown, it could indicate an absorption problem at the
もしわずかに茶色い場合、それは
level of the liver and gallbladder.
肝臓と胆嚢の吸収の問題である可能性があります。
If it's red, it can also be related to the heart and liver.
もし赤い場合、それは心臓と肝臓にも関係している可能性があります。
Or if it's hazy, it could be a toxic problem.
あるいは、もし濁っている場合、それは毒性の問題である可能性があります。
for those who have drunk too much alcohol, smoked too much, or taken too many drugs.
飲みすぎたり、吸いすぎたり、薬を使いすぎたりした人たちです。
I will not go into the details of the eye now.
今は目の詳細には立ち入りません。
But in any case, already, within this conjunctiva, it is important.
しかし、いずれにせよ、この結膜は重要です。
It can become inflamed, for example, following a minor distant infection,
例えば、遠隔の小さな感染症、
such as a minor appendicular or digestive issue.
例えば小さな虫垂炎や消化器系の問題の後に炎症を起こすことがあります。
It can manifest here.
それはここで表現されることがあります。
We call it conjunctivitis or a stye,
結膜炎やものもらいと呼ばれ、
which can also be a deficiency in certain minerals.
それは特定のミネラルの欠乏であることもあります。
And the way to treat it is simply not to touch it too much,
そして、その治療法は、あまり触らないこと、
apply warmth.
温めることです。
a lactose intolerance, for example. You see, we will observe the importance of the
例えば乳糖不耐症の場合、腸間膜軸を持つ消化器系の免疫系の重要性がわかります。
immune system within the
免疫系は
digestive system, with the mesenteric axis carrying a lymphatic
リンパ系と免疫系を支える腸間膜軸を持つ消化器系において、
and highly significant immune plan.
非常に重要です。
We could say that the ileocecal valve is an early tonsil. You have the eyelid...
盲腸のバフォンは早期の扁桃腺であると言えるでしょう。まぶたが垂れ下がっているような人がいますが、
these people like that who have a kind of ptosis like that, it
これはある種の眼瞼下垂のようなもので、
can in some cases be
場合によっては、
problems of poly-
多発性
cystic kidney disease.
腎臓のヒストシス。
A lady who comes with significant lumbar pain, somewhat elderly.
腰痛がひどく、少し高齢の女性が来院しました。
Then you look at her head and you see that she probably really has a...
彼女の顔を見ると、おそらく本当に...
Yes, I would request an ultrasound.
はい、私は超音波検査を依頼します。
The white of the eye with a whitish expression can be a sign of hypercholesterolemia.
白っぽい目の白は、高コレステロール血症の兆候である可能性があります。
Sometimes, you also have small, grayish fatty deposits directly on the eye
時には、目の上にわずかに灰色がかった脂肪沈着物が見られることもあります。
-brown.
-茶色。
Like this, it can also be a sign of hypercholesterolemia.
このように、高コレステロール血症の兆候である可能性もあります。
You have the iris.
虹彩があります。
And then you have a kind of line here.
そして、ここに一種の線があります。
And if it is quite firm here, like this, it can indicate a hypoacidic stomach,
そして、もしそれがここでしっかりしていれば、それは低酸性で、
hypotonic.
低緊張の胃を示している可能性があります。
Whereas if it's the same, but much more open, like this,
一方、同じことでも、もっと開いている場合は、
you have an expression of a hyperacidic stomach.
高酸性の胃の表現です。
Around here, you can sometimes see in certain blue eyes,
この周りには、時々、特定の青い目で、
dotted white lines around, like this.
点線のような白い線が見られることがあります。
This is the lymphatic ring; it indicates a deficiency.
これはリンパの輪で、欠損を示しています。
Then we can also have what are called more nervous rings, spasms
そして、神経性の輪、痙攣と呼ばれるものが見られることもあります。
that will appear.
それが起こります。
And then you still have the entire study of the stromal texture, etc., and specific positions.
そして、フレームワーク全体の研究など、特定のポジションがあります。
This originates from a very deep level; it can be related to that, when it's slightly yellowish,
それは非常に遠くから来ており、わずかに黄色がかった場合、それに関連している可能性があります。
depending on the colors that will appear in certain types of eyes,
特定の種類の目に見られる色に応じて、
it can indicate gastric issues and more specifically.
それは胃の問題、より具体的には、
this well-known candidiasis found in the intestine, the fungi.
腸に見られる有名なカンジダ症、真菌の問題を表す可能性があります。
It is important to have a tongue with good luster, a pink tongue,
舌が良好な光沢を持ち、ピンク色で、
not too red, not white, mobile, responsive.
赤すぎず、白すぎず、動きがあり、注意深いことが重要です。
The tongue must be moist; if it is very red, it can indicate a problem towards the
舌は新鮮であるべきで、非常に赤い場合は、心臓の問題を表す可能性があります。
heart.
心臓。
If it is very white, it can indicate a problem towards the stomach, but one must go into detail.
非常に白い場合は、胃の問題を表す可能性がありますが、詳細に入る必要があります。
Do not forget, regarding the tongue, you have what is called the color of the tongue and you have
忘れないでください、舌のレベルでは、舌の色と呼ばれるものがあり、
the tongue coating.
舌のコーティングがあります。
There is a coating. The coating is generally slightly posterior.
コーティングがあります。コーティングは一般的にわずかに後方にあります。
And the coating represents a state of gastric or hepatic reflection
そして、コーティングは胃、肝臓、
or colonic.
または結腸の反射状態を表します。
If I look here and I have a deposit like this, somewhat crown-shaped, I must consider
もし私がここを見て、このような沈着物、少し王冠のような形をしている場合、私は考えるべきです。
that it is a delicate colon.
それはデリケートな結腸です。
sensitive. Here, on the side, it indicates a fragile lung. This,
敏感です。ここでは、側面は脆弱な肺を表します。これは、
is already more of a
すでに気管支炎であり、これはすでに肺炎のような泡です。側面、ここでは、
bronchitis, and this is already more of a pneumonia-type exudate. On the side, here, laterally,
肺が見えます。側面、ここでは、腸と
I will observe the lungs. On the side, here, I will observe the intestine and
胃が見えます。歯にひび割れがある人々は、側面で、舌全体が
the stomach. Individuals
まるで噛んだかのように見えます。さて、彼らは死を経験している人々です。
who have cracks in their teeth, there, on the side, they have a tongue
これらは適切に同化されない食品です。
as if they had bitten, there, on the side. Well, these are individuals who have a death
結腸に毒素がある場合、後方のコーティングが見られます。
here.
ここに。
But if it is truly thick, it can indicate a thick whitish coating, it
しかし、もしそれが本当に厚いなら、それは白っぽい厚さを示すかもしれません。
can indicate what is known as gastric reflux.
それは胃食道逆流症と呼ばれるものを示すかもしれません。
Observe with the eyes and with the symptomatology, because in the eye, at the level
目と症状で見てください。なぜなら、目の虹彩のレベルで、
of the iris, you can observe a hypotonic stomach.
低緊張の胃を見ることができるからです。
This is a very common pathology.
これは非常に一般的な病状です。
Esophagitis issues, with stomach problems, are very common.
食道炎の問題、胃の問題は非常に一般的です。
You can also observe a line that divides the tongue in two,
舌を二つに分ける線も見ることができます。
which can indicate, if there is a deviation, for example here,
例えば、ここに偏りがある場合、それは
a lumbar problem, or a dorsal problem, or a cervical problem.
腰の問題、または背中の問題、または首の問題を表すかもしれません。
This is the line of the vertebral column.
それは脊椎の線です。
You show the tongue to someone, and the tongue, does it only do you?
誰かに舌を見せると、舌はあなただけですか？
It is very common.
それは非常に一般的です。
trembles like this. Renal problem with an excess of panic. The tip of
このように震えます。パニックの過剰を伴う腎臓の問題。舌の先端が
the tongue here red,
ここが赤い、
very red, or here can indicate a cardiac problem. If, in addition, you
非常に赤い、またはここが心臓の問題を表すかもしれません。もしさらに
observe a line of
あなたが線の
completely red baux here, be cautious. When I observe posteriorly here, it will indicate the state
完全に赤いバウズをここに見るなら、注意してください。私がここで後方に見るとき、それは
of colonic or stomach type. On the side here, I will rather observe the pulmonary aspect,
結腸または胃の状態を表します。ここの側面では、私はむしろ肺の側面を持つでしょう。
a trembling tongue, or further back, you see the deposits in the posterior midline.
震える舌、または後ろに、後方中央の堆積物が見えます。
rather areas of toxins that will
むしろ毒素の空間が
manifest in the body. The gastric
体の中に現れるでしょう。胃のコーティング、
coating, do not forget. Reflux, very common.
忘れないでください。逆流は非常に一般的です。
Reflux can express,
逆流は、
can be associated with digestive,
問題に統合される可能性があります。
ENT, or
消化器系、耳鼻咽喉科、
genital problems
または生殖器系の問題に
in women as well. Slightly
女性でも。わずかに
moist, supple,
湿っていて、しなやかで、
that protrudes easily,
簡単に出る、
where there isn't much coating.
コーティングがあまりないところ。
Pathological conditions
病状は
begin when the color
色が変わり始めるときに始まります。もし舌が
changes. If the tongue
もし舌が
If the tongue is white, it is a sign of cold in the body, insufficient energy in
もし舌が白いなら、それは体の中に冷えがある兆候であり、体の中に十分なエネルギーがなく、
the body, indicating a slowdown in metabolic activity.
代謝活動が遅くなっていることを示します。
If the tongue is yellow, it is a sign of dampness in the body, indicating
もし舌が黄色いなら、それは体の中に湿気がある兆候であり、
heat in a particular organ, colonic, stomach, lung
特定の臓器、結腸、胃、肺、
or posterior kidney.
または後方の腎臓に熱があることを示します。
Kidney problems will be found more here.
腎臓の問題は、ここにより多く見られます。
If the tongue is red, it is a sign of cold.
もし舌が赤いなら、それは冷えの兆候です。
fire; if the tongue is green, it is a sign of the Wood element, meaning it is an activity
もし舌が緑色なら、それは木のサイン、つまり活動が
of toxins that are not released. If the tongue is rather gray or black,
毒素が排出されていないことを意味します。もし舌が灰色または黒っぽいなら、
it is a sign
それは
of parasitosis or toxemia. Thus, the evolution of the color indicates
寄生虫症または毒血症の兆候です。したがって、色の変化は
the deep penetration
病理の深部への浸透を
of the pathology. The coating is essentially a reflection of the
示します。舌苔は主に胃の反映です。厚ければ厚いほど、
stomach. The thicker it is,
厚ければ厚いほど、
the more the stomach
胃が
is affected. You can sometimes have a very smooth tongue, even a
侵されています。時には非常に滑らかな舌、あるいは少し痛みを伴う舌を
minimally painful,
持つこともあります。
which has lost its papillae, indicating an imbalance, a deficiency
乳頭が失われ、リボフラビン、ニコチン酸、葉酸、ビタミンB12の欠乏による
in riboflavin,
不均衡を
in niacin, folic acid, vitamin B12. Note,
示しています。注意してください、
medications can
薬は
alter the state of the tongue. If you have a hairy tongue, it
舌の状態を変化させる可能性があります。もし毛深い舌をしているなら、それは
indicates a toxic etiology.
毒性のある原因があることを示しています。
If the tongue is very swollen like this, it may indicate minor organic affections
もし舌がこのように非常に膨らんでいるなら、それはそれに伴う小さな器質的疾患を
depending on the specific presentation.
示す可能性があります。
Pay attention if you observe a tongue deviation.
舌の偏位がある場合は注意してください。
When you protrude the tongue, it deviates in this manner.
舌を出したときに、このように偏位するのです。
This may indicate a sign of cranial nerve paralysis, specifically
それは脳神経の麻痺の兆候を示す可能性があります。特に舌下神経、
the hypoglossal nerve, the 12th cranial nerve.
第12脳神経です。
On the tongue, this entire area here will represent the stomach.
舌の上では、この領域全体が胃を
and the large intestine.
そして大腸を表します。
This part here will indicate the renal zone.
この部分はむしろ腎臓の領域を表します。
This part here may indicate the liver on the right,
この部分は右側に肝臓、
the spleen,
脾臓、
and then the entire pulmonary zone here.
そしてここには肺の領域全体を表すことができます。
The central line will represent the vertebral column,
中央線は脊椎を、
and then here you have the entire cardiac zone,
そしてここには心臓の領域全体があり、
and then at the top, you have the entire zone extending superiorly to the stomach level here.
そして上部には胃のレベルまで続く領域全体があります。
I have made a combination,
私はここで、
A combination here between Ayurvedic medicine and Chinese medicine.
アーユルヴェーダ医学と中国医学を組み合わせました。
Subsequently, there may be deposits, depending on their configuration.
次に、これらの沈着物がどのように配置されているかによって、沈着物がある場合があります。
I must assess if it indicates toxemia.
それが毒血症であるかどうかを確認する必要があります。
Do not forget, there is the color of the tongue,
忘れないでください、舌の色があります。
whether it is white or excessively red,
白か、赤すぎるか、
whether it is green or black.
緑か、黒か。
This will indicate different states.
それは異なる状態を表します。
If it is trembling, if it is cracked,
もし震えていたり、ひび割れていたりしたら、
thus, it will express the state of the internal organs.
それは内臓の状態を表しています。
Therefore, this means that the tongue almost always reflects the true state of our patient.
つまり、舌はほとんど常に
The color is affected by recent changes.
患者さんの本当の状態を反映しているということです。
The color is more useful in chronic diseases, whereas
色は最近の変化によって影響を受けます。
the coating is generally more useful in acute cases.
色は慢性疾患においてより有用であり、
Pay attention to the consumption of foods that can momentarily affect
舌苔は一般的に急性疾患においてより有用です。
these aspects.
一時的に影響を与える可能性のある食品の摂取に注意してください。
of the color. All medications, especially corticosteroids, anti-inflammatory drugs,
物事を。
all anti-cancer type medications can modify.
色について。薬、特にコルチコステロイド、抗炎症薬、
tous les médicaments de type anti-cancéreux peuvent modifier.
すべての抗がん剤は変化させる可能性があります。